原视频名：Perseverance Rover's Descent and Touchdown on Mars (Official NASA Video)
原作者名：NASA
视频来源：youtu.be/4czjS9h4Fpg
原视频发布日期：20210222
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
We are starting the straighten up and fly right maneuver,
现在开始直着向前飞 机动
where the spacecraft will jettison the entry balance masses in preparation for parachute deploy
也就是航天器会抛弃再入平衡质量块 并准备部署降落伞
and to roll over to give the radar a better look at the ground.
同时调整姿态 让雷达对准地面
[inaudible] indicates chute deploy.
[听不清]显示降落伞展开
The navigation has confirmed that the parachute has deployed
导航系统确认降落伞已展开
and we are seeing significant deceleration in the velocity.
同时我们注意到速度在明显下降
Our current velocity is 450 meters per second at an altitude of about 12 kilometers from the surface of Mars.
我们目前的速度是450m/s 处在距离火星表面约12km的高度
Heat shield sep.
隔热板分离
Perseverance has now slowed to subsonic speeds and the heat shield has been separated.
毅力号现在已减速到亚音速 隔热板也已分离
This allows both the radar and the cameras to get their first look at the surface.
雷达和相机因此能首次看到火星表面
Current velocity is 145 meters per second
目前的速度是145m/s
and an altitude of about 10 kilometers - nine and a half kilometers above the surface.
同时距离火星表面约9.5km的高度
Nav filter converge. Lastly solution 3.3 meters per second, altitude 7.4 kilometers.
导航滤波器收敛 最终方案3.3m/s 高度7.4km
Nav has radar lock on the ground.
导航雷达已锁定地面
Current velocity is about 100 meters per second, 6.6 kilometers off the surface of Mars.
目前速度约为100m/s 距离火星表面6.6km
Perseverance is continuing to descend on the parachute.
毅力号正在继续使用降落伞下降
We are coming up on the initialization of terrain relative navigation
我们即将进行地形相对导航的初始化工作
and subsequently the priming of the landing engines.
并随后启动着陆发动机
Our current velocity is about 90 meters per second at an altitude of 4.2 kilometers.
我们目前的速度大约是90m/s 高度为4.2km
LVS valid.
着陆器视觉系统(Lander Vision System)启动
We have confirmation that
我们已经确认
the lander vision system has produced a valid solution and part of terrain relative navigation.
着陆器视觉系统产生了有效的解决方案和部分地形相对导航
Priming.
发动机正在注入燃料
PBA is nominal.
PBA(?)正常
We have priming of the landing engines.
我们对着陆发动机进行了燃料注入
Back shell sep.
后壳分离
Current velocity is 83 meters per second at about 2.6 kilometers from the surface of Mars.
目前速度为83m/s 距离火星表面约2.6km
We have confirmation that the back shell has separated.
我们确认后壳已经分离
We are currently performing the divert maneuver.
我们目前正在进行转移机动
Current velocity is about 75 meters per second
目前速度约为75m/s
at an altitude of about a kilometer off the surface of Mars.
距离火星表面约1km的高度
TRN safety bravo.
地形相对导航安全完成
We have completed our terrain relative navigation.
我们已经完成了地形相对导航
Current speed is about 30 meters per second,
目前的速度大约是30m/s
altitude of about 300 meters off the surface of Mars.
距离火星表面约300m的高度
We have started our constant velocity accordion
我们已经开始了匀速下降
which means we are conducting the skycrane - about to conduct the skycrane maneuver.
这意味着我们差不多在进行天空起重机机动
Skycrane maneuver has started.
起重机机动已经开始
About 20 meters off the surface.
距离地面大概20m
We're getting signals from MRO.
我们收到了来自火星勘测轨道飞行器的信号(MRO=Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter)
Tango delta.
探戈德尔塔(北约音标字母)
Touchdown confirmed.
确认着陆
Perseverance safely on the surface of Mars,
毅力号安全抵达火星表面
ready to begin seeking the signs of past life.
准备开始寻找过去生命存在的痕迹